April 20, 1648 Testament Era
4:58 A.M., Honda Tadakatsu Manor, Mikawa
4:58 A.M.
Honda Futayo's Room
This morning was the same as any other. Nothing particularly stood out.
Everything was as usual.
Walk yonder path, walk yonder path
I thought these days would last forever,
but they shatter as they draw to an end.
Set out now, perchance to find
the narrow path to Gods does wind
Do not say such, its perils much
When the time comes, I...
What do you see?
You, as you are now,
lock your heart until you've summoned the strength you need
What do you hear?
Shall we speak of bygone days
in this secret, little room?
My memories embraced all mysteries and smashed them
with quiet prayers I overcame my suffering
and a new world began
I didn't know whether men could accept the future
like drinking wine
and threw all I had away
This new world lies in the vale between cold reason and utter miracles
Why was it here that I could meet you?
2:12 P.M.
Highway to Kakamigahara Checkpoint No.1, Mikawa
Covert Ops Under the Night Sky
2:17 P.M.
Highway to Kakamigahara Checkpoint No.1, Mikawa
Show me!
Score!
2:53 P.M.
Diner on the Outskirts of Mikawa
Damn, Sakai!
You're still groping girls' butts in battle?
People don't usually sic their kid on their big-shot buddy either.
Futayo, was it?
You're one tough cookie!
Father, could you properly introduce us?
Oh, me? I'm Sakai Tadatsugu,
the true leader of the Four Divine Matsudaira Kings.
Back in the day,
Lord Matsudaira Motonobu was the school president and eternal student council president.
I was the chancellor and your dad was the commando unit's captain.
I was vice president, moron!
Ii was the vice president
and Sakakibara here was nothing but talk.
That's not true!
I was the clerk and an expert in the humanities.
Girlie, isn't it time you overcame your athlete father's brainwashing?
Girlie?
Care to join my academy?
I'm dying to enroll someone like you!
Honda Masazumi's there.
Remember her?
I haven't seen Masazumi since middle school,
but I heard she moved to Musashi.
Isn't she the vice president?
She sure is! So, why don't you enroll?
I'm honored by your offer, but...
Hold it, Sakai.
Futayo is currently working as the colonel of the Mikawa Guard.
Wow!
Colonel of the only Far East armed force approved by the Testament Union, eh?
Intrigued?
Actually,
Futayo is leaving Mikawa on a vanguard soon to ensure Musashi's safety
through the corridor to Aki.
I told her she may do as she pleases once she reaches Aki.
Meaning?
My father and I agreed that I should decide everything for myself.
Save the invitation until then, Sakai.
I'm sure Futayo will accept if she feels she needs you or Musashi.
The world is ready for change
and I want my daughter to make her own path.
I see...
Peerless Man of the East, Honda Tadakatsu's prized warrior is heading out
just as Peerless Man of the West, Tachibana Muneshige
is succeeding that name in Tres España.
Gah!
Kazuno?!
I see it's none other than Master Sakai.
Honda, you're still letting her live with you?
I don't have a choice!
No one can replicate my wife's cooking
or swordplay quite like she can.
Plus, she has perfect etiquette.
Judge.
I am currently teaching Lady Futayo the basics.
Lady Futayo is a mature woman now,
but Master Tadakatsu still tries to bathe with her
or take her to a grill.
He's most deplorable.
His nickname "Dacchan" is short for "deplorable human".
Do not speak ill of Master Tadakatsu.
Honda, she still has that demonic rule
where she's the only one allowed to insult you?!
Master Tadakatsu, it's time to prepare the ship.
Judge, judge.
Well, I'm off.
Keep up the good work!
5:30 P.M.
In Front of the Diner on the Outskirts of Mikawa
Sakakibara, tell me two things.
Tell me about Ii.
Does his absence today mean something happened to him?
And there's an automated doll named P-01s on Musashi.
She boarded from Mikawa last year, so what's her deal?
Sakai, do you know about the spiriting away incidents called the "Lost Nobles"?
6:09 P.M.
Above the Normal Land Port, Mikawa
6:11 P.M.
Prefecture Highway 79, Mikawa
So, she's gone...
A Tres España Inquisition Warship came in as they were departing.
In that case...
Tachibana Muneshige should be aboard.
How exciting,
although I'll never get the chance to see Futayo fight him.
Master Tadakatsu, it is time.
Got it. I'll be quick.
We will hereby begin preparing the fireworks.
Everyone, please commence your assigned tasks.
Lord Motonobu, things are proceeding as planned.
They'll find out about the fireworks at just past eight.
But do you think he's okay with this, Kazuno?
Judge.
He was enjoying himself.
It was an appropriate farewell.
I see.
I don't understand your thinking,
but I shall serve you until the very end.
Commence operations and watch the show as our lord.
Enjoy Mikawa's final fireworks, which will turn the world against us.
6:59 P.M.
Kakamigahara, Mikawa
Go!
B1T3 to B2T3.
We're on duty, so no standing.
I can see you from here!
What's wrong?
What?!
I dealt with B2T3.
The results were favorable.
I dealt with B1T3. Same outcome.
7:44 P.M.
Tea House Next to Sakakibara Manor
Master Sakai, this is for you.
Oh, thanks.
Where's Sakakibara?
Judge.
Before he began working on the materials, he ordered me to deliver them to you, which I've now completed.
Did he forget something?
It's blank!
Dammit!
Master Sakai?
Please pursue the kidnappers.
It's okay.
I believe the Four Divine Matsudaira Kings will always be together.
7:51 P.M.
Sakakibara Manor Study
Sakakibara!
The master isn't in, so I believe he's finished his work.
I would like to begin cleaning the room.
Not you too, Sakakibara...
Pursue the Nikyou Crest
"Pursue the Nikyou Crest"?
Genesis Project
"Pursue the kidnappers"?
7:53 P.M.
Musashi Ariadust Academy
Go, go!
N-Nenji!
I bet the chancellor had a hand in all this.
Honestly, what was he thinking?
W-Water...
What's going on here?!
Who brought this chaos upon my town?!
Speak now if you wish to say something.
Suzu!
Whoa! Warning! Warning!
He made the girl with the cutest bangs in Musashi cry!
H-Hey! Chancellor and president!
Is this madness your fault?!
You get the death sentence!
O-Over there...
Think there was an accident at the Testament Union's guard post?
Divine Contact
I can't say.
I tried contacting the chamber of commerce, but I can't get through.
All right, let's break for now!
Wait!
Me?
Behind...
Behind you! Behind you!
Behind me?
A girl?
Sh-She's ghostly!
Papa's gone.
I can't find Mama.
It...
It's a ghost!
7:57 P.M.
In Front of Sakakibara Manor
The Kakamigahara Guard Post?
Honda?
You've sure gotten older if you couldn't dodge that!
Slicing Dragonfly?
That's a Shinto weapon!
Hey, that noise!
Is it coming from the ground?
No, it's from deeper down.
It's...
The Earth's plates.
Is it the Shin-Nagoya Platonic Plate Reactor?
What are you doing?!
We're starting a meltdown.
You're what?!
7:59 P.M.
Shin-Nagoya Castle, Mikawa
Central Unification Reactor, Mikawa
7:59 P.M.
That'll destroy all of Mikawa, not just Nagoya!
No one's left in Mikawa.
It's just the automated dolls and us.
What did you discover?
I'm in the dark.
Our lord has only informed me that this is the beginning of the Genesis Project.
Genesis Project
The Genesis Project?
I know that it could potentially save us all.
I wouldn't do that!
I'll bind you!
You'll bind me?
Slicing Dragonfly can sever things from existence.
Is the Kakamigahara Guard Post burning...
Because I severed the guards' very existence.
Honda, why?!
Go, Sakai.
I don't have time to fiddle with you.
Kazuno and I have to intercept those Testament Union bastards.
Moron, they'll kill you!
I don't care.
My display of loyalty is to protect my lord's wishes and prevail.
So Tadatsugu, where does your loyalty stand?
Don't you want to see what happens next?
So go, you no longer belong here.
Honda!
What about your daughter?
What's that?
We've reached a stop and shall begin turning back.
Fluid output erupting from Shin-Nagoya Castle is increasing.
Detection levels have increased a notch.
Tres España's armed guard is taking action.
A fleet of landing craft is approaching Mikawa.
K.P.A. Italia put our call on hold rather than blocking it.
The Testament Union ships dispatched the Gods of War and commenced an assault.
Let them make their move.
Ma'am?
They'd use anti-aerial mountain gear for putting out a fire.
But if this was all just a feint...
You don't think Mikawa is...
This way the Testament Union can force their armament into Mikawa.
Lady Futayo!
What would you have us do?
Gather all officers on the ship.
Judge!
"Do as you like," eh, Father?
He wanted me to handle this myself.
What would Masazumi do?
8:01 P.M.
Deck Bow, Tama
Isn't that...
Have the fireworks begun?
Fireworks? Fireworks?
That's no firework.
So, no fireworks?
Too bad, so sad!
Judge.
We need to get away from here.
And go where?
We might learn something if we drop by Blue Thunder.
Later!
My power just went out!
That light absorbs power if you touch it!
Damn, how do we handle that?!
Notice from Base-1:
It has been proposed that the Gods of War clear the way for the unit
ordered to destroy the Platonic Plate Reactor in Shin-Nagoya Castle.
But we're in anti-aerial gear!
We will send backup.
Tes!
A1 and A2 are to charge in.
A3 is to gather information and provide backup.
Tes!
8:01 P.M.
Prefecture Highway 79, Mikawa
One down.
What happened, Zaragoza?
You're losing altitude!
H-HQ, we were fired upon from the ground.
An automated doll fired at us!
It's Kazuno from Mikawa's Honda clan!
Horned witch!
Swords at my command!
A shield before me!
Increase numbers.
Reform.
Hurry it up! We're running out of time.
I know!
It doesn't make sense.
Excuse me?
Why would the people of Mikawa trigger a meltdown in the Platonic Plate Reactor
when it could destroy the whole prefecture?
Master Muneshige, only Mikawa's locals know the answer to that.
Then, I'll have to ask one.
Isn't that pretty?
Are these Lord Motonobu's "fireworks"?
But this is...
This is a man-made meltdown!
Our communications indicate Mikawa's automated dolls
are rising up against the Testament Union.
I bet Kazuno is leading the rebellion.
That means my father, Tadakatsu, is certainly involved in this.
Lady Futayo, we could use this ship to aid Sir Tadakatsu.
We must decide what course of action is most beneficial for the Far East.
Any opinions on this?
Ma'am!
If Mikawa intentionally started the meltdown,
the Testament Union will revoke its position as
the Far East's representative and lay claim to Musashi.
They would gain a great deal if they overtook the Far East and Musashi.
The worst-case scenario for us is the best-case for them.
So we're the only ones who can stand between Musashi and the Testament Union.
We had little contact with Musashi because we're from Mikawa.
Lady Futayo?
Right now, we should stand by and remain completely neutral.
But doesn't that betray what's in your heart?
Judge.
Loyalty is only given meaning through one's actions.
Very well.
Head of Communications, contact the Testament Union.
Tell them we wish to help in the event of an emergency.
Judge!
Entering standby!
Await word from the Testament Union.
Got that? We're on standby!
Judge!
That night, our world began to change.
When I awoke this morning, I thought this world would never change.
The days I thought would last forever drew to an end,
as we embarked on a journey with no return.
Not that I knew that back then.
I gather my dented courage and walk forward
because I swore to myself I would create my own future
Shower your light, O Star, upon the melody sprung forth here
and let me see your smile by my side
I kept on calling your name even as pain stabbed my body
I hope you will hear me some day, above the distant horizon
Next Episode
Graduates Under the Moon