April 20, 1648 Testament Era
4:58 A.M., Sagarmatha Corridor
5:00 A.M.
Asama Shrine, Okutama
Same Time
Asama Tomo's Room
To ráno bylo stejné jako všechna předchozí.
Walk yonder path, walk yonder path
Nebylo na něm nic zvláštního.
Svět vypadal stejně jako vždy.
Set out now, perchance to find
Ten neměnný klid našeho života
the narrow path to Gods does wind
se ale začínal hroutit.
Do not say such, its perils much
Tehdy jsem...
What do you see?
You, as you are now,
lock your heart until you've summoned the strength you need
What do you hear?
Shall we speak of bygone days
in this secret, little room?
My memories embraced all mysteries and smashed them
with quiet prayers I overcame my suffering
and a new world began
I didn't know whether men could accept the future
like drinking wine
and threw all I had away
This new world lies in the vale between cold reason and utter miracles
Why was it here that I could meet you?
2:12 P.M.
Musashi Ariadust Academy
Commandos in Town
2:15 P.M.
Musashi Ariadust Academy Student Dorms
Tady to bude.
Co si...
Promiň!
Musel jsem si splést pokoj.
Miriam Poquou?
Okutama
Dear Azuma,
We wish to inform you that we have selected a room for you.
Musashi Ariadust Academy Student Dorm:
Okutama 1-15-26
Kdo mi s tímhle poradí?
To je mi přivítání. Dva z Macudairových Čtyř nebeských králů,
2:17 P.M.
Highway to Kakamigahara Checkpoint No. 1, Mikawa
samotní Jasumasa Sakakibara a Tadakacu Honda.
Kde máte Iiho?
Jak bych to řekl...
To je tajné, Sakakibaru.
Sem s tím!
Ne tak rychle, Hóňo!
Když takhle vybafneš, většinou to nedopadne moc...
Plác!
To bylo o fous!
A teď chci vysvětlení.
2:37 P.M.
Residential District, Tama
Hele, fakt si nemyslíš, že jsme to s tím nákupem přehnaly?
Podle mě toho máme tak akorát.
Zítra bude oslava.
Hm, oslava.
Hlavně abychon nedopadli neslavně.
Ve vzduchu je docela nával.
Hlídky z Tres España opustily stanoviště,
tak začali kurýři pořádat závody a cvičné souboje.
Možná tam s nimi jsou i Naruze a Knight.
Počítám, že ty dvě večer taky přijdou.
A v Mikawě bude ten ohňostroj.
Počítám ale, že vy taky radši půjdete na tu oslavu.
J-já jdu také!
Máte o Tóriho starost, že?
Celý svět řeší Odu, zbraně smrtelných hříchů a konec světa
a my se strachujeme, jestli jednomu šaškovi nedá holka košem.
Není to žádná Píseň o cestě, ale jeden by se bál.
Co se asi tak Tórimu honí hlavou? Teď, když se připravuje na své vyznání.
Očekává nový začátek, nebo změnu pohledu na svět?
Kimi je určitě připravena na cokoliv.
Pokud Tórimu vše půjde hladce, nejvíc to odnese ona.
Ten pitomec se ale někam vypařil.
Kimi pořád sedí na schodech, že?
Jo. Když jsme se rozcházeli, Tóri prohlásil, že jde na Třídu lítosti.
Celých deset let se jí ten hlupec vyhýbal.
Ale Kimi...
Bláznivá sestra, která dává pozor, jestli se její střelený bratříček přemůže a Třídu projde.
Sedí a čeká.
Řekla bych, že všechno začalo u Horizon.
Horizon byla hodné děvče.
D-Did you know?
Whenever Tori talks to me,
he starts with, "Hey!" or, "So like," every time.
And when he offers me his hand or gets ready to go,
he does this.
That's his sign.
I can't see,
so he does that to give me a heads up.
Yeah, and we started following suit.
Horizon was the one who started that.
Even though Horizon's gone, Tori hasn't forgotten about her.
Indeed.
Huh?
You were out shopping too?
Just how big is this party gonna be tomorrow?
We're gonna be buried in food!
What's going on?
I've had a lot of customers from the Academy since this morning!
Sorry!
We might be causing a ruckus tomorrow, though.
Are you throwing a party or something?
Then I might have to ask P-01s to go all out.
A party?
I guess.
Yes, I think everything will work out!
After all, everyone's hoping that it'll be a fun party.
2:37 P.M.
Transportation District, Murayama
Niello Trade
I know!
I think this is gonna be a blast!
So, Malga, aren't they holding a rising altitude race in the weighted atmosphere?
Wanna enter?
Sounds good.
Let's enter one after work.
We can make some money off the admirals and marines.
Thanks!
Later!
Say, Malga, can you see Kimi?
Judge.
She hasn't moved, so she's still in my sights.
Doesn't that mean the chancellor hasn't budged?
It sure does. Care to make a comment?
You bet I do!
I've got a rush delivery for the student council.
Working Class Man
The shipping label clearly says,
"Highest Peak! The Virgin Queen Elizabeth, 1st Edition."
I bet the chancellor ordered this.
Are you going to feel bad for him or make fun of him?
It was disguised as an educational program,
but he messed up the label.
So it seems...
Oh, it's Seijun!
Hey!
What's up?
I just got back from Mikawa.
Margot, is Masazumi there?
Tell him about the package and what's going on tonight.
Seijun, the Chancellor's exorcising ghosts at school tonight.
See you there?
Uh, no, I live in Murayama,
so I'd have to go through the guard post to visit Okutama at night.
That would upset my father.
Isn't your dad a big shot on the Provisional Council?
Uh, I guess...
Then this is for you.
It's addressed to the student council.
Musashi, Far East Okutama
Musashi Ariadust Academy
To: Student Council
Lightning Delivery
Breakable!
"Highest Peak! The Virgin Queen Elizabeth,
1st Edition."
Why is this going to the student council?!
The chancellor oughta be close to Remorse Way about now.
I think you should go see him.
Why?
Because, Seijun...
Whoa! What's going on?!
A race!
C'mon, little missy!
Pass that on to the chancellor!
Ritual Summons
Work's Title
"When One Falls Asleep"
Operate 5 Times
The chancellor and Kimi, eh?
3:03 P.M.
Musashi Ariadust Academy Student Dorms
You should come on in.
What's keeping you?
A-Are you sure?
Um, the Academy assigned me here as of today.
That's fine.
It's not like I've never shared a room before.
Although, it will be my first time with a boy.
I-In that case—
We'll just have to adjust.
A-Are you sure you don't mind living with a boy?
Would you leave if I asked?
After you first arrived, you went and requested a different room.
But it was rejected, so you've been standing outside the door.
Y-Yeah...
Can you promise me something?
Promise?
Right.
We mustn't interfere with each other's personal affairs.
Let's see.
An extreme example would be
that I couldn't complain even if you came back with a girl.
I'd never do that!
I'm teasing!
Do you know who I admire?
People who are dense, but earnest.
Uh...
I don't question those who are dense and earnest.
You can come back if you're afraid,
my silly brother.
Whoo!
Huh?
You just had to destroy the mood right when it was getting good.
What's Tori doing?
Is that some new game?
Or should I go whack him?
Teacher, I heard you were drinking in the cafeteria,
so what brought you out here?
I just needed to cool off, I guess.
Oh, don't use your hands!
It will damage your hair.
Just leave it to me.
What's so funny, Teacher?
Well, see,
I just remembered how an old lady in my neighborhood used to do this.
Teacher, being drunk is no excuse for comparing me to an old woman.
What is it?
You can do it. You can...
Teacher, are you on my silly brother's side?
You bet I am!
I'll always side with everyone in our class, not just Tori.
But I can't interfere with any student affairs.
What's that?
It's Masazumi.
3:35 P.M.
Spiritual Shrine Heian, Okutama
Spiritual
Shrine
Heian
Spiritual
Shrine
Heian
Shomen Street
I'm on the right path.
Rejoice, my child now is ten of age
P-01s?
and will need charms 'gainst heaven's rage
The journey might be bliss eternal
but downwards 'gain is
Out at last!
fear infernal
I've heard that voice a lot today.
What are you doing here, Masazumi?
Father!
There is still much for me to learn about Musashi,
so I was investigating the area.
Did you learn anything about the rest area in the woods you just stumbled out of?
What about the rest area?
Your research was insufficient
if you didn't learn anything.
Sir...
Your son is holding a most unusual item.
Huh?
I accept items like that in my business deals.
The first edition is most rare!
Musashi, Far East Okutama
Musashi Ariadust Academy
To: Student Council
Lightning Delivery
Breakable!
"Highest Peak! The Virgin Queen Elizabeth,
1st Edition."
Oh, no, this is...
I don't know what it is, but let him have a look at it.
But this is my friend's...
Masazumi!
Hey!
Huh?
Sweet! Good job, Seijun!
Thanks a bunch!
I just gotta play this tonight,
and Knight and Naruze were taking forever!
Aoi, you look awful!
Are you okay?
Don't worry, I'm just winded from running!
Tomorrow, I'm gonna tell the girl I love how I feel.
So we're partying on campus tonight.
You coming?
Of course not!
It's against school rules.
If I'm going anywhere, it's to see Mikawa's fireworks.
I was really hoping you'd make it.
You know the girl I'm gonna confess to really well.
W-Wait a sec!
This won't take a lot of time, will it?
I can't say!
I'm sorry about that.
No worries.
I'm surprised to see the Master of Remorse Way out here.
It's been a good decade!
The Master of Remorse Way?
Look over there.
Okay...
A girl died in an accident around here a long time ago.
The one on the monument?
Judge.
May the young lady,
Horizon A., rest in peace.
~Residents of Musashi
Her name was Horizon Ariadust.
Isn't Ariadust the Academy's name?
When Lord Motonobu became the head of Mikawa thirty years ago,
he took the first syllable in the Matsudaira name
and flipped it backwards.
Thus, he changed his name from Matsudaira to Ariadust.
It was to show his allegiance to the Testament Union.
The Testament Union acknowledged his loyalty and changed his name back,
but there were some who kept that name.
Haven't you heard?
Lord Motonobu had a common-law wife and child.
Well...
The child's name was Horizon Ariadust.
Don't forget it!
Lady Horizon got into an accident with Lord Motonobu's carriage.
He was headed for a function celebrating approval for repairs to Musashi.
It will have been ten years tomorrow.
It was a long time ago,
but it must replay in real time for the Master of Remorse Way.
The end results suggests
that he killed Lady Horizon.
What do you mean he killed her?
Then what's the secret behind everyone's words "pursue the truth"?
It's about Aoi Tori's "remorse".
It's a play on words with Remorse Way.
He was injured when they rushed him and Lady Horizon to Mikawa.
But he came back alone.
All that remained was his remorse.
Then, how is he still able to laugh?
Why does everyone give him their support?
"Why," eh?
Will you pursue this, Masazumi,
and see where his remorse takes him?
I'm running late for my meeting.
We're finished here.
So I'm still in the dark, huh?
6:09 P.M.
Above the Normal Land Port, Mikawa
Isn't that...
Indeed. It is the "Peerless Man of the East" Honda Tadakatsu's daughter, Honda Futayo.
Please stand proudly and look straight ahead,
"Peerless Man of the West" Tachibana Muneshige.
I know.
My current job is to keep an eye on Mikawa and the Pope President.
Despite my inability to do anything but fight,
they treat me like quite the political pawn.
Please do not lose.
Do not bring me sadness.
Very well.
7:00 P.M.
Kakamigahara Guard Post, Mikawa
B1T3 to B2T3.
We're on duty, so no standing.
I can see you from here!
But I was sitting!
7:30 P.M.
Musashi Ariadust Academy
So then, is everyone here?
Judge.
Tori isn't here yet.
And what'd you do with the elementary schoolers living here?
Fool! Their parents are the ones who matter!
They pay the bills.
Shiro, you rock!
Excuse me...
What is it, Asama?
I'd like to warn everyone about something before we begin the exorcism.
Fine, go ahead.
But don't spend any money.
I won't.
You know how rumor has it that the end of the world is coming?
Supernatural events have been occurring across the land.
One you should be aware of is the spiriting away of entities into Lost Nobles.
Most consider these events urban legends,
but last year a case was reported in the Far East.
It was Masazumi's mother.
I-I can't listen to this!
Kimi, I know you can't stand scary stories, but really!
Pipe down over there!
Be quiet!
Kimi, calm down!
Okay, I'm late!
Sorry, my bad!
The prep took a while.
Let's get started!
He isn't hiding the fact that he set traps, huh?
Nope...
7:44 P.M.
Hallway in Front of the Library
How's it look, Asamachi?
I haven't seen a damn thing.
I hope they make some kind of ghostly noise that we can recognize.
I-I can't handle noises!
It's okay.
There's nothing around here.
But well, over there...
Bullseye!
Wh-What?!
What was over there?!
Don't worry about it.
You'll be fine as long as you stay close.
That doesn't make me feel any better!
Adele, you should've brought your mechanic shell if you're so freaked out.
Nah, it's an older model, so it's insanely heavy.
Whoa!
Library
The library?
Right. This is where our job ends.
Now, then...
What are they?
New faces!
Hey, moron! What'd you do?!
I didn't do anything.
I asked them to!
Who?!
It better be someone we can pay off.
Yahoo!
Huh?
Waha!
Until then, I believed
we wouldn't change even if Tori confessed his feelings.
I thought the world would never change.
7:59 P.M.
Shin-Nagoya Castle, Mikawa
And that we would greet a happy tomorrow as always.
Towards the sky strives
our sailing voyage across the real world
Although I own nothing
I have sparkling dreams within my heart
So far I can not make out what your heart has to say
but I want to know, show me your true self
Countless things have been scattered all across the world
We will find them one by one and fill the void
Someone stole your smile from you
These days I run to retrieve it
down a path shining with light
Next Episode
Covert Ops Under the Night Sky